SahilAnand Design Technologist

I have a deep and broad background in software, hardware and robotics. I research, design and build prototypes for proof-of-concept, demonstration and testing of emerging technologies. By combining UX design and engineering expertise into a single discipline, I inspire development teams and senior leadership to invest in new ideas that solve real-world consumer and enterprise problems.

EDUCATION

MS in Human Centered Design and Engineering

University of Washington, Seattle | Sep 2015 - Mar 2017 (Expected)

B.Tech in Electronics and Communications Engineering

National Institute of Technology Karnataka, IN | Aug 2006 - May 2010

WORK EXPERIENCE

Design Technologist Intern

Amazon, Seattle | June 2016 - Sep 2016

- > Researched and prototyped a system for user experience researchers to **capture and analyze the emotional experience of users** interacting with Amazon Digital Products and Devices.
 - » Designed and implemented the **complete end-to-end workflow** consisting of tools for data capture, upload, emotion analysis, and reporting. Built innovative solutions to simplify the workflow by automating different components.
 - » Created **interactive visualizations** to represent the temporal and task-level emotional experience of participants interacting with products.

Graduate Teaching Assistant, Human Centered Design & Engineering

University of Washington, Seattle | Mar 2016 - June 2016

- > Teaching Assistant for HCDE 439: Physical Computing, an undergraduate level class that introduces students to concepts and practices of engineering human-centered interactive systems and environments using low cost microcontrollers, sensors and actuators.
- > Responsibilities included assisting lecturer in preparation of course content, assisting students with learning and understanding, grading and providing feedback on homework and assignments.

Student Researcher, Human-Centered Robotics Lab

University of Washington, Seattle | Oct 2015 - June 2016

- > Researched, designed and created functional prototypes to evaluate:
 - » Social and Conversational Robots for teaching English to children in rural Africa.
 - » 3D Interfaces for Robot Tele-Operation and Interactive Manipulation.
- > Co-authored publication titled "Automatic Adaption of Online Language Lessons for Robot Learning" at the International Conference on Social Robots, ICSR 2016

CONTACT

syanand@uw.edu (206) 954 8144 sahil-anand.com

SKILLS

UX

User-Centered Design
User Research
Usability Testing
Wireframing
Interaction Design
Data Analysis
Rapid Prototyping
Information Visualization

Design Tools

Adobe Creative Suite Autodesk Maya, 123D Proto.io Makerbot Makerware

Programming

C/C++ Java Python HTML, CSS Javascript Arduino

Frameworks

ROS
Unity
Django
Meteor
Angular
Bootstrap

WORK EXPERIENCE (contd.)

Student Assistant, Department of Urban Design and Planning

University of Washington, Seattle | Oct 2015 - Mar 2016

- > Designed and developed:
 - » Interactive **mapping and visualization tools** for visualizing risks and natural hazards.
 - » MVP and functional prototypes for a web-based tool to enable users to search for a specific land parcel and receive a visual and statistical report describing its vulnerability to natural and human-health related hazards.

Full Stack Engineer + Designer, (Core Founding Team Member)

IIL Technologies Pvt. Ltd, Bangalore, India | Apr 2012 - Sep 2015

- > Designed and developed **multi-platform solutions** for clients to improve marketing strategies and customer engagement for their products :
 - » Performed **complete UCD lifecycle** and led the **implementation** and **deployment** of solutions.
 - » Increased Customer Engagement by 3X and Sales Conversion from 7% to 25% in first month.
 - » Enabled timely and data-driven decisions, reducing reaction time from 1 week to few seconds.
- > Created MVPs, mock-ups, software and hardware prototypes for validating product ideas with potential users and for product demos to clients and investors.

Technology Consultant, Research and Development

India Innovation Labs (IIL), Bangalore, India | Jun 2010 - Sep 2015

- > Researched and developed Robotics, Computer Vision and Natural User Interface technologies
- > Collaborated with industry partners to research, develop and evaluate numerous software and hardware prototypes and applications for emerging technologies.
- > Mentored 20+ undergraduate engineering students in Robotics and Computer Vision projects.